Register of the British Library of Information collection
Hoover Institution Archives
British Library of Information collection
1920-1921
XX214
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
The collection includes clippings from American newspapers in English, French, and German, collected by the British Library of Information in New York City. The clippings focus on American sentiment towards Great Britain and the British Empire in 1920-1921.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Arrangement Statement
The collection is organized into 3 series of clippings, arranged by language: English; French; and German.
Biographical/Historical note
The British Library of Information was a branch of the British Foreign Office News Department created in 1919 to improve relations between the United States and Great Britain. This was done in two ways: firstly, by dispensing officially approved information about Britain’s domestic, imperial, and foreign affairs through the Library’s reading room; and secondly, by monitoring American public opinion through newspaper clippings, which were collected and sent to the Foreign Office. The Library proved to be an adequate dispensary and collector of information for the Foreign Office during peacetime, but with the onset of World War II, it could no longer meet the goals or demands of wartime foreign policy. Consequently, it was absorbed into the larger British Information Services in 1942. Further information on the British Library of Information can be found in David Lincove’s article, “The British Library of Information in New York: A Tool of British Foreign Policy, 1919-1942.” Lincove, David A. "The British Library of Information in New York: A Tool of British Foreign Policy, 1919-1942." Libraries & the Cultural Record 46.2 (2011): 156-84. Web.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection includes clippings from American newspapers in English, French, and German, collected by the British Library of Information in New York City during 1920-1921. The clippings focus on American sentiment towards Great Britain and the British Empire, especially in relation to the establishment of the Irish Free State, the anticolonial movement in India, the Versailles peace settlement, and the Anglo-Japanese alliance.
British Library of Information (New York, N.Y.); Great Britain--Foreign relations--Japan.; India--History--British occupation, 1765-1947.; Ireland--History--1910-1921.; Japan--Foreign relations--Great Britain.; Journalism--United States.; World politics.; World War, 1914-1918--Peace.
- English Language Clippings, 1920-1921
  - December 1920 - January 1921 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - 1921
    - April - May (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - June - September (Box-folder 1: 3)
- French Language Clippings, 1921
  - 1921
    - July - August (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - September - October (Box-folder 1: 5)
- German Language Clippings, 1920-1921
  - 1920 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - 1921
    - May - June (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - July - August (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - September - October (Box-folder 1: 9)